Guide to the Thomas James Massey Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Thomas James Massey papers
1978-2009
SC1066
Massey, Thomas James, 1948-2009.
1.5 Linear feet
Collection includes biographical materials; materials related to Massey's dissertation research on the African American higher education experience; notes; news clippings related to Massey's achievements at Stanford; photographs; program files; printouts of email correspondence; notes; and a journal related to events attended by Massey.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Thomas James Massey, ’69, MA ’72, worked in a variety of roles in student affairs at Stanford University, including as assistant dean of student affairs and as assistant director of the Graduate Life Office. He co-authored the book Mediation: Transforming Conflict Through Communication, and started Faces of the Community, a New Student Orientation program highlighting diversity on campus. Massey died January 1, 2009.
Description of Collection
Collection includes biographical materials; materials related to Massey's dissertation research on the African American higher education experience; notes; news clippings related to Massey's achievements at Stanford; photographs; program files; printouts of email correspondence; notes; and a journal related to events attended by Massey.
Access Terms
Woodward, Denni.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Dissertation (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ewart Thomas' Comments (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 000330 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Obituary/Memorial Services, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CV, circa 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation Proposal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Passages (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program Evaluation Information (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Program Evaluation Information (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - SU intergroup dialogue building alliances through sustained civic engagement (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - J. Gregory Dees, The Meaning of Social Entrepreneurship., 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Email re: Culture & Diversity Education Offical Realm (CANDOR), 2007 Dec 14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - News clippings, 2003-2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mosaic Project, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Center-Mediation & Communication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photos (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Articles (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Mountain (Poetry) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Black Students (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notes (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Souls on the Line (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Email re: NACC & Culture & Diversity Education, 2007 Nov 7 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Journal: S.C. Learning Expedition, St. Helena, SC, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)